[Episode 8]
Captain Di, can't you go easy on us?
Exactly, we can't win at all.
A bet's a bet.
Only by winning do you get half a day off.
It's a tradition.
Who else wants to try?
Your Majesty.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
No need for these formalities
during training.
All of you, rise.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Nian,
haven't seen you in a few days,
and your skills have really leveled up.
Your Majesty, you flatter me.
I have not sparred with you
for quite some time,
and my hands are truly itching for a bout.
If you want to spar with His Majesty,
you'll have to get past me first.
Don't forget. Last time we fenced,
you still owe me a drink.
You only have your eye on my meager salary.
I'll definitely win next time.
The Divine Guard was personally trained
by the late Marquis back in his day.
Now that it's in your hands,
I am very gratified.
Nian.
You have not dishonored your family's legacy.
Father once said,
the Divine Guard is Ning's sharpest spear,
and must always be kept sharp.
Just like the Marquis,
you will also stand on your own
and guard the border in the future.
I remember your youthful ambition
was to don armor and go into battle.
But now, you are trapped within the palace,
serving as my shield.
My father passed away early.
Your Majesty, it was you who gave me a place
to settle and find purpose.
Now, protecting you
is my most honorable battlefield.
I do so willingly.
Now, with you and Di Nian by my side,
it's like having my left and right arms.
The safety of the capital and me
rest on the shoulders of you two.
Nian,
I have one more thing to entrust to you.
Select 12 light cavalrymen
and train them in secret.
Your Majesty, you mean...
You will know when the time comes.
Yes, Your Majesty.
The scholars enter the hall.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
May Your Majesty
be blessed with boundless fortune.
I just bought
some Dong'e donkey-hide gelatin.
Everyone, try some.
Everyone, have a taste.
- Here.
- Then I'll have one too.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Come on.
Meng.
Today is the day the results are posted.
Don't worry.
You will definitely pass the exam.
Don't be nervous.
Fu Zhi, I'm not nervous.
But could you please stop pinching me?
Here they come.
Good news!
Where is An Qing,
the scholar from the capital?
Here. I'm here.
Congratulations, Scholar An.
You are the 16th Jinshi of the second rank.
I passed! I passed!
Where is Zuo Qiu Rong from Jingzhou?
I'm here!
You have passed
as the 13th Jinshi of the third rank.
I passed too!
Where is Lu Xiao Wan from Qingzhou?
I'm here!
The 16th Jinshi of the third rank.
I passed. I passed too!
Fu Zhi.
What about your rank? Did something go wrong?
I intentionally approached His Majesty
in the palace.
He found out that I was eavesdropping
on his discussion of state affairs.
Maybe I angered him.
His Majesty's moods are unpredictable.
He wouldn't punish you, would he?
He is the Son of Heaven.
Surely he wouldn't be so petty, would he?
Meng Ting Hui, scholar of Shazhou,
receive the decree!
Granted.
After careful review of the exam rites,
and the talent selection in the Palace Exam,
Meng Ting Hui from Shazhou Women's Academy
ranked first and is entitled Zhuangyuan.
This is hereby proclaimed to the world.
Fu Zhi.
It's me.
It's really me.
I won the title of Zhuangyuan!
Hesitation always means a troubled mind.
Lord Xu,
His Majesty has proclaimed to the world
that Meng Ting Hui
is our first female Triple First Zhuangyuan.
With such favor,
her future prospects are likely limitless.
The new Zhuangyuan?
It is just a hollow title.
Since she hasn't been granted a real post,
we can send her back to her hometown
to await orders.
Lord Xu, you're indeed a step ahead.
Truly a veteran minister plans for the state.
I submit.
[Zhuangyuan]
In the first Special Exam of Ning,
the title of Zhuangyuan
goes to Meng Ting Hui, scholar of Shazhou.
Congratulations, Zhuangyuan Meng!
In the first Special Exam of Ning,
the title of Zhuangyuan
goes to Meng Ting Hui, scholar of Shazhou.
[Zhuangyuan]
Make way.
Meng Ting Hui
really won the title of Zhuangyuan.
Triple First? That's incredible.
Our Chunman House has hosted a literary star.
Ma'am, we must pay our respects
when we get back.
Definitely. I'll take you to pay respects
when we return.
Okay.
- Zhuangyuan Meng once stayed at our inn.
- Zhuangyuan Meng!
Really?
- Miss Meng!
- Zhuangyuan Meng! Zhuangyuan Meng!
Come to Chunman House!
Meng!
Meng! Meng!
Meng, I'm here!
Look.
[Congratulations on achieving Triple First]
Look. Look over here!
With talent as vast as the ocean,
you'll have everything you desire.
She's my best friend!
We came together!
Meng, look!
Congratulations to Zhuangyuan Meng!
Look!
Zhuangyuan Meng!
Congratulations.
Zhuangyuan Meng.
See? We're very close.
Zhuangyuan Meng!
Congratulations.
Look at this location.
In the entire capital,
Changle Street is the most prosperous.
Look at the shop you're considering.
In front is the renowned signboard
of Lingluo Hall.
Next door
is the long-established Yanzhi Pavilion.
Across the street is Chunman House.
If the owner
didn't have pressing family matters,
he'd never
be willing to sublet such a prime shop.
Great!
This shopfront looks spacious and impressive.
With a little tidying up,
it can open for business right away.
If I make the most authentic mutton noodles,
my shop would outshine Chunman House any day.
I really like this shop. I'll take it.
Ms. Yan, you are truly straightforward.
Then pay the deposit today, and you can
get the license from the Envoy of Customs.
The Envoy of Customs?
What does the Envoy of Customs do?
The Envoy of Customs oversees the operations
of all the merchants in the capital.
From inspecting ingredients and shop safety,
to collecting taxes.
Speak of the devil.
Mr. Shen here is the Envoy of Customs.
Who did you say?
Who in the whole capital doesn't know
Mr. Shen Zhi Shu?
To open a restaurant,
you'll need to get the license from Mr. Shen.
If you're lucky,
you can open for business in three months.
Why would it take so long?
We're right under the Emperor's nose.
Naturally, the rules here are much stricter.
The capital is not short of business people.
The licenses are issued in limited numbers.
If one doesn't have a local official
to act as a guarantor,
waiting for a year or so is quite common.
If I had known,
I wouldn't have kicked him out.
Alright, let's talk about it next time.
Mr. Shen.
Here.
Pretending not to know me?
Mr. Shen.
My apologies.
I already reserved this room
with the manager.
I didn't know you were still here.
We came specifically for you.
Mr. Shen.
Come in.
We've booked the entire Chunman House today.
So we are all you've got.
We've even prepared a vintage wine for you,
Chunfengzui.
Let me pour some for you. Please, try it.
Thank you.
Mr. Shen, try it.
How is it?
I'll also fill your cup.
Mr. Shen, it's been a while.
You've lost quite some weight.
He was skinnier as a child.
When we were young, his father
insisted on arranging a betrothal between us.
I was the one who stubbornly refused,
so he gave up the idea.
Now that I think about it, I really regret it.
Speaking of childhood,
Mr. Shen helped me chase away hornets
during the Shangsi Festival that year.
Unexpectedly, he got stung
and swelled up like a fat-headed fish.
I have a better story.
As a child, he helped me catch small fish
in the river.
He ended up falling into the river
and became a drowned rat.
Why bring up things from the past?
I have matters to attend to today,
so I'll take my leave now.
Sit down! You're not going anywhere!
Zhi Shu!
We swore our love to each other
under the moonlit flowers in Shazhou.
How come you've forgotten all about me
once we arrived in the capital?
So it turns out you have two new sweethearts.
Who is she?
I am the one he holds in his heart,
the one he will marry with all proper rites.
Who do you think I am?
Sorry.
My wife has a fiery temper.
Please forgive us.
Wife?
You shameless man!
You scoundrel!
You...
Old habit.
Ms. Yan.
Although you helped me
out of a tight spot today,
could you find a better way next time?
Tell me. How are you going to thank me,
your savior?
According to the stories, a life-saving debt
should always be repaid with marriage.
But between us, let's forget it.
I'm still in shock.
Ms. Yan, if you have something to say,
just say it directly.
Fine. I'll get to the point then.
I plan to open a branch of Bofeng House
in the capital,
serving the most authentic Shazhou cuisine.
I've already picked the location,
right next door.
But I've heard
that getting a license can take a year or so.
So I'd like to ask you to be my guarantor
and make things easier.
I knew you were up to no good.
Just apply according to the procedure.
If you're selected,
someone will naturally notify you.
You must agree.
- What if I refuse?
- You...
If you refuse,
I'll never speak to you again in the capital.
Ms. Yan, your way of asking for a favor
is truly unique.
But I am not one to fall for that.
Farewell.
Ten jars of Shaosanbai wine.
What? I didn't hear you clearly.
Plus special Shazhou wine.
I advise you not to push your luck.
I need to see your sincerity.
How about this?
Cook me a table of Shazhou dishes yourself.
Dream on!
Then I'll just have to go drink elsewhere.
Stop.
Ten jars of Shaosanbai wine,
five jars of the special Shazhou wine,
and a table of dishes I cook.
Take it or leave it.
It would have been so much better
if you were this straightforward earlier.
Ms. Yan,
next time you want to see me,
just send a note.
No need to go through such a big detour
like today.
You...
Watch your tone.
This is the capital.
Get lost.
Who wants to see you?
- What did you say?
- I said,
"Get lost! Who wants to see you?"
[Shen Mansion]
Thank you, Master.
Uncle Gu, long time no see.
Zhi Li,
Mother and Father prepared a banquet long ago
to celebrate your success in the exam.
Why are you only coming back now?
Uncle Gu,
we won't trouble you anymore.
I'll take Zhi Li home.
May you remember your scholarly aspirations,
and may your future be as vast as the ocean.
Your post at the Hanlin Academy
is already set.
Remember. The imperial place
is the best for tempering one's character.
Here.
Thank you, Master.
Uncle Gu, you should also go home early.
Don't worry your wife.
If you have time,
remember to bring her to visit us.
Go on now.
- Your parents are waiting for you.
- Uncle Gu is right.
Don't keep Mother and Father waiting.
Let's go, Zhi Li.
What did you just call me?
You're being disrespectful.
Call me sister.
Sister.
Mother and Father
made a lot of delicious food today.
You've been so busy with the Palace Exam.
You've lost a lot of weight.
You must eat more later.
The last dish,
my dear wife's favorite sweet and sour ribs.
Let me try one first.
Sit down and eat.
Thank you, Father.
Mother, we owe a lot to you today.
I haven't had Father's cooking
in a long time.
My handsome jawline is getting so sharp.
It's becoming way too obvious.
When the cat's away, the mice will play.
In my opinion,
you are living quite comfortably.
You were appointed as the Envoy of Customs,
indulging in poetry and romance every day.
Did you ask His Majesty for this position?
Mother, look at Father.
I'm doing serious, important work.
Is it up to me to decide
what His Majesty asks me to do?
You accused him of being a playboy, and now
you suspect him of currying favor for a post.
What? Do you want your son
to be like those pedantic scholars,
always wearing a stern face,
before you're satisfied?
Thank you, Mother.
His Majesty made him the Envoy of Customs.
So many eyes are watching.
Any misstep will eventually give his enemies
the ammunition to attack him.
Don't let his laid-back attitude fool you.
In real business, he never messes around.
His Majesty values him, so he entrusted him
with such an important task.
Dear sister, my love for you all these years
hasn't been in vain.
Thank you, Father.
Father, when it comes to the Envoy position,
I'm the only one in the entire court
who can truly pull it off.
I may have lived a life of luxury
on ordinary days,
but the intricacies involved
are quite profound.
Such arrogance!
Others crave a path to success,
but you just drive yourself into a dead end.
Before, you were at least a Court Advisor.
And now?
You even have to submit a request in advance
just to attend the court session.
Look at Nian.
He's been more sensible than you since young,
never making your mother and me worry.
He always thinks of us in everything.
Thank you, Father.
- Zhi Li.
- Nian, give it to me.
Lacking ambition and constantly showing off,
you'll pay a heavy price sooner or later.
Come on, Father. Try some.
Mother.
You don't even resemble me in the slightest.
Even less like your mother.
Look at Nian.
What part of my eyes, nose, or mouth
doesn't look like yours?
Nian, Nian, Nian.
Anyone who doesn't know
would think Nian is your real son.
If that were truly possible,
I would certainly want Nian to be my son.
The Di family is full of loyal martyrs.
At 18, Nian could already inspect the border
on behalf of His Majesty.
You? Entertain His Majesty with amusements.
Where is the dignity of a court official?
Stay out of the palace.
His Majesty should be accompanied
by loyal and upright ministers like Nian.
Wasn't that all for his sake?
Alright, Zhi Shu.
Enough talk.
That also requires His Majesty
to be able to do without me.
If I don't enter the palace, in three days,
His Majesty will come out to find me.
Listen to him! What a load of nonsense!
Can His Majesty not hold court without you?
Nian, eat.
You are the oldest child,
yet you are the most worrying.
Anyone who doesn't know
would think you're the youngest.
That's because I was born well.
That's because you're foolish!
Father, Mother.
Isn't today supposed to be a celebration
for Zhi Li winning the Bangyan title,
and landing her dream posting
at the Hanlin Academy?
I even prepared a gift for her.
Look at that. We forgot the main business.
Li, your father and I
also prepared a gift for you.
Thank you, Nian.
My gloves were just about worn out.
Nian is the most considerate.
Li, take a look at this too.
Your father made these writing materials
back in the day.
This inkstone was made of the Lanshan stone
gifted by the late Emperor.
It stays warm in winter and cool in summer,
and keeps the ink fresh.
Thank you, Father. Thank you, Mother.
When I entered officialdom,
how come I didn't see anyone giving me gifts?
What should we give you?
Gambling chips made of golden-thread nanmu,
or dice carved from jade?
Or pay to redeem
a few more of your lady confidantes?
Father, am I your real son or not?
Why do you oppose me at every turn?
If you really think
I've tarnished the honor of the Shen family,
I'll leave right now.
Zhi Shu.
It's fine. I'm full.
Shen Wu Chen,
must you hurt him deeply
before you're satisfied?
You clearly care deeply,
yet you pierce his heart with every word.
Zhi Shu has been doing very well
all these years.
It's precisely because His Majesty treats him
as his best brother,
and relies on him in every way,
the court is even less tolerant
of any mistake he makes.
The words of those censors
are three times sharper than swords.
So you, as his father,
decide to point your sword at your son first?
Look.
This is the soup you personally made,
his favorite.
He didn't even take a sip.
[Chunman House]
The appointment from Ministry of Personnel
still hasn't arrived.
I don't know how much longer I have to wait.
Meng, maybe it's because
your official position is so good
that the pedants at the Ministry of Personnel
need to deliberate over and over.
Zhuangyuan Meng,
the Ministry of Personnel sent a document.
Coming.
Thank you.
Hurry!
Let's see which cushy job it is.
Return to hometown and await orders?
This is impossible.
I specifically went to inquire today.
All the female officials from the same cohort
received notices and went to their posts.
Shen Zhi Li and Jinshi Zuo Qiu Rong
were both assigned to the Hanlin Academy.
Everyone has been assigned.
Only I am told to go home and wait.
It seems someone
is determined to cut off my official career.
Meng, you are the Zhuangyuan
personally selected by His Majesty.
Who is so bold as to block your appointment?
Who else could it be but Lord Xu?
Fu Zhi, I can't just sit here and do nothing.
I must find a way to enter the palace
and see His Majesty before dawn.
We'll figure it out together.
Anyway, I have money, and you have brains.
Nothing can stop us.
Zhuangyuan Meng,
Lord Xu requests your presence.
Meng,
he wants to see you so late at night.
He must be up to no good.
Maybe he wants to silence you.
They've completely blocked the exits outside.
We're trapped here with no way out.
I must go.
Come on, my dear ministers.
Have another drink with me.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
The new Zhuangyuan, Meng Ting Hui,
has arrived.
Meng Ting Hui, the Imperial Exam Zhuangyuan,
pays respects to Your Majesty.
May Your Majesty
be blessed with boundless fortune.
I summoned you to the palace tonight
in the name of Lord Xu to test your courage.
You actually dared to come alone.
Good! You have guts.
Give Zhuangyuan Meng a seat.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Meng Ting Hui,
you achieving the Triple First
has truly brought me great honor.
I am very pleased.
I only had this opportunity
thanks to Your Majesty's protection.
I will certainly not fail your grace
and will share your burdens.
My dear ministers,
let's toast to Zhuangyuan Meng together.
To Zhuangyuan Meng.
I am in a good mood today.
I also have a major announcement to make.
Lord Xu has arrived.
Your Majesty,
you used my name
to summon Meng Ting Hui to the palace.
Why didn't you inform me in advance?
You're even drinking?
Lord Xu, you're here?
Today, the Imperial Exam for Women
has concluded successfully.
I am pleased,
so I invited the ministers to drink together.
Lord Xu.
- Come have a drink with me.
- Your Majesty.
Having served three reigns,
I've never seen a monarch act so improperly.
Meng Ting Hui,
the document from the Ministry of Personnel
didn't reach you?
This is a banquet for sixth-rank officials.
Are you even qualified to sit here?
Lord Xu, you even personally
inquire about a lowly nobody like me.
So the order asking me to return and wait
was really your doing.
Hold on.
Return and wait?
The female Zhuangyuan with Triple First
I selected to be entrusted with vital tasks
became an idle person
with nowhere to be placed?
Lord Xu, what is the meaning of this?
Your Majesty, please see clearly.
Currently, there are no vacancies
within the six ministries.
If we assign her hastily,
wouldn't it be a waste of her great talent?
Come on, Huo An.
Escort Miss Meng back to Shazhou
to await her appointment.
Since the six ministries
cannot place Meng Ting Hui,
send her to the Censorate.
The Heihu Crew in Shazhou,
the Huxiao Gang in the capital,
Ding Chong who acts as their accomplice,
and those like Dong Shou Cai
who deceive the court and mislead the people.
How many more demons and monsters
are there in this land?
You lot!
You all turn a blind eye and play dumb,
as if nothing is happening.
Then I will establish the Censorate
to eliminate the injustice of this world.
Your Majesty,
do you think we are all incompetent?
You want to establish a new institution
and employ such inexperienced newcomers?
Let me ask you then.
You are so impatient
to expel the talent I chose from the capital.
What exactly are you trying to do?
Your Majesty,
establishing a new institution
is a matter of great importance.
If we decide hastily,
I'm afraid it'll cause turmoil in the court.
I've made up my mind.
Starting today,
Meng Ting Hui will be the Director,
independent of chancellors and ministries.
She will report directly to me.
I accept the decree.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Since we need experience,
it would be more lively with more newcomers.
Shen Zhi Li, as the Bangyan,
isn't it boring to face old papers
at Hanlin Academy all day?
Starting today, transfer her to the Censorate
to assist Meng Ting Hui.
I accept the decree.
Your Majesty,
to entrust such a heavy duty to two girls
will simply cause chaos for the court.
I beg you to withdraw your decree.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty.
Lord Xu, your rosewood dragon-head cane
may suppress the seals of the six ministries.
Do you want to suppress my imperial seal too?
Lord Xu, you use your seniority
to act arrogantly,
going against my will repeatedly.
Do you really think
I can't do anything to you?
Your Majesty, do you know what you are doing?
I was just joking with Lord Xu.
Lord Xu.
Did you really think I would hurt Lord Xu?
Lord Xu is a pillar of Ning.
Come on.
Everyone, have a drink with Lord Xu.
Your Majesty, you are drunk.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, be careful.
Drink with Lord Xu on my behalf.
His Majesty never drinks.
How did he get so drunk today?
Zhuangyuan entering the palace?
It's clearly a sorceress.
[Imperial Study]
Your Majesty, slow down.
Your Majesty,
it's so late. Will Miss Meng really come?
[Imperial Study]
Imperial Guard Huang,
has His Majesty retired for the night?
Please, Imperial Guard Huang.
[Imperial Study]
The banquet is over.
Why haven't you gone back?
Your Majesty, you summoned me.
When did I ever summon you?
Since Your Majesty didn't,
I will take my leave.
Why don't you bow when you see me?
I, Meng Ting Hui,
pay respects to Your Majesty.
I was worried that appointing you
as the Director of Censorate was too risky.
Now, it seems that was unnecessary.
If you truly thought that way, you wouldn't
have pretended to be drunk tonight
and went to great lengths to stage this act
to promote me.
You tried so hard to approach me.
Wasn't it for the post in the Censorate?
I have granted your wish.
But the heart of a monarch is hard to fathom.
A few days ago, you refused me.
Yet today, you promoted me publicly,
disregarding Lord Xu's opposition.
I cannot see your mind clearly,
and that makes me even more uneasy.
I gave you power beyond the two chancellors.
What more do you want?
Do you have other designs?
Your favor seems like a blessing,
but isn't it also placing me
in the line of fire?
If you insist on a return,
I am willing to risk my life
to fully investigate the Huxiao Gang case.
I ordered the investigation of Huxiao Gang,
but to this day, there is still no lead.
How can a mere folk gang be so powerful?
Your Majesty, you suspect
Huxiao Gang has influence in the court?
Without a conclusion,
one must not speak recklessly.
I await your surprise.
I am willing to be the sharp blade
in your hand.
But now, it's hard
to distinguish friend from foe in the court.
I hope to select the Censorate members
all by myself.
Apart from this, Zhi Shu and Di Nian
will assist you in the investigation.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
That one.
It's here.
Keep digging.
Okay.